
const data  = [
    {
        id: 1,
        question: "What is the purpose of Redux reducers?",
        options: ["To specify how component state should change in response to actions", "To specify how the state in a Redux store should change in response to actions", "To specify how component styles should change in response to actions", "To specify how component events should change in response to actions"],
        answer: "To specify how the state in a Redux store should change in response to actions",
    },
    {
        id: 2,
        question: "Which of the following command is used to Install create-react-app?",
        options: ["npm install create-react-app", "npm install -f create-react-app", "npm install -g create-react-app", "install -g create-react-app"],
        answer: "npm install -g create-react-app",
    },
    {
        id: 3,
        question: "Which hook is used to add state to functional components in React?",
        options: ["useState","useEffect","useContext","useReducer"],
        answer: "useState"
    },
    {
        id: 4,
        question: "What does JSX stand for?",
        options: ["JavaScript XML", "Java Syntax Extension", "JSON Xchange Schema", "JavaScript Xerography"],
        answer: "	JavaScript XML"
    },
    {
        id: 5,
        question: "What is the significance of the virtual DOM in React?",
        options: ["It renders components on the server side.", "It optimizes React components for mobile devices.", "It provides an in-memory representation of the DOM for efficient updates.", "It handles animations and transitions in React applications."],
        answer: "It provides an in-memory representation of the DOM for efficient updates."
    },
    {
        id:6,
        question:"Which method is used to update the state of a class component in React?",
        options:["this.updateState()","this.setState()","this.modifyState()","this.changeState()"],
        answer:"this.setState()"
    },
    {
        id:7,
        question:"Which of the following acts as the input of a class-based component?",
        options:["Class","Props","Factory","None of the mentioned"],
        answer:"Props"
    },
    {
        id:8,
        question:"Which of the following is used to pass data to a component from outside in React?",
        options:["props","render with arguments","setState","PropTypes"],
        answer:"props"
    },
    {
        id:9,
        question:"What is ReactJS?",
        options:["Open-source JavaScript back-end library","JavaScript front-end library to create a database","Free and open-source JavaScript front-end library","None of the mentioned"],
        answer:"Free and open-source JavaScript front-end library"
    },
    {
        id:10,
        question:"What is the purpose of React Fragments?",
        options:["To group multiple components within a single parent component.","To create reusable CSS styles for React components.","To optimize the rendering performance of React components.","To handle asynchronous operations in React applications."],
        answer:"To group multiple components within a single parent component."
    },
    {
        id:11,
        question:"State the Keyword Used to Declare Block-Scoped Variables in ES6?",
        options:["block","var","let","const"],
        answer:"let"
    },
    {
        id:12,
        question:" Which of These is Used to Declare a Constant Data Type?",
        options:["constant","const","cont","cnst"],
        answer:"const"
    },
    {
        id:13,
        question:"What is the Role of the JavaScript Engine?",
        options:["Compilation","Interpretation","Parsing","Compilation and parsing"],
        answer:"Interpretation"
    },
    {
        id:14,
        question:"Where Should You Insert JavaScript Code in an HTML Document?",
        options:["The <head>section","The <body> section","Both <head> and <body> section","Anywhere in the HTML file"],
        answer:"Both <head> and <body> section"
    },
    {
        id:15,
        question:"Which Function Does Not Return a Value?",
        options:["Dynamic function","Method","Static function","Processes"],
        answer:"Processes"
    },
    {
        id:16,
        question:"Which Function is Used to Eliminate the Last Element From the Array?",
        options:["pop()","deleteLast()","splice()","removeLast()"],
        answer:"pop()"
    },
    {
        id:17,
        question:"What is the Role of Object-Oriented Programming in JavaScript?",
        options:["Code organization into classes and objects","Elimination of the function needs","Faster code execution","Shorten the code length"],
        answer:"Code organization into classes and objects"
    },
    {
        id:18,
        question:"Which is Used to Calculate String Variables in JavaScript?",
        options:["let","var","const","All of the above"],
        answer:"All of the above"
    },
    {
        id:19,
        question:"Which amoung the following is a server side javascript object?",
        options:["file upload","funciton","file","typeof"],
        answer:"file"
    },

    {
        id:20,
        question:"The latest HTML standard is",
        options:["XML","SGML","HTML 4.0","HTML 5.0"],
        answer:"HTML 5.0"
    },
    {
        id:21,
        question:"What is the preferred way for adding a background color in HTML?",
        options:['<body background="yellow">','<background>yellow</background>','< body style="background-color:yellow">','<background color="yellow">text<background>'],
        answer:'< body style="background-color:yellow">'
    },
    {
        id:22,
        question:"Which of the following JavaScript cannot do?",
        options:["JavaScript can react to events","JavaScript can manipulate HTML elements","JavaScript can be use to validate data","All of the Above"],
        answer:"All of the Above"
    },
    {
        id:23,
        question:"Whats so great about XML?",
        options:["Easy data exchange","High speed on network","Only B is correct","Both A & B"],
        answer:"Both A & B"
    },
    {
        id:24,
        question:"Which is not a property of attribute Behaviour of <Marquee> tag?",
        options:[" alternate","blur","scroll","slide"],
        answer:"blur"
    },
    {
        id:25,
        question:"Which browser can supports the transition property?",
        options:["Internet Explorer 10","Firefox","Chrome","All of the above"],
        answer:"All of the above"
    },
    {
        id:26,
        question:"How can you make a list that lists the items with numbers?",
        options:["<ul>","<list>","<ol>","<dl>"],
        answer:"<ol>"
    },
    {
        id:27,
        question:"Which of the following is NOT a Style?",
        options:["Linked","Embedded","Inline","Orthogonal"],
        answer:"Orthogonal"
    },
    {
        id:28,
        question:"Identify the most accurate statement about the application of XML?",
        options:["XML must be used to produce XML and HTML output","XML cannot specify or contain presentation information","XML is used to describe hierarchically organized information","XML performs the conversion of information between different e-business applications"],
        answer:"XML is used to describe hierarchically organized information"
    },
    {
        id:29,
        question:"Which of the following statement is not true regarding JavaScript?",
        options:["JavaScript is an object-based language","JavaScript is event driven","JavaScript is a loosely typed language","A JavaScript embedded in an HTML document is compiled and executed by the client browser"],
        answer:"A JavaScript embedded in an HTML document is compiled and executed by the client browser"
    },
    {
        id:30,
        question:"The href attribute in the link tag specifies the__________",
        options:["Destination of a link","Link","Hypertext","None of the above"],
        answer:"Destination of a link"
    },

]

export default data;